* en

* en

Privacy Policy of Scamadviser
=============================

June 19, 2024

ScamAdviser's work conforms to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) requirements when processing personal data. This means we: 

* clearly specify our purposes before we process personal data by using this privacy statement; 
* limit our collection of personal data to only the personal data needed for legitimate purposes; 
* first, ask for explicit permission to process your personal data in cases where your permission is required; 
* take appropriate security measures to protect your personal data, and we demand the same from parties who process personal data on our behalf; 
* respect your right to access, correct or delete your personal data held by us

ScamAdviser (formal company name: Ecommerce Operations B.V.) is responsible for all data processing. This privacy statement explains what personal data we collect and for what purposes. We recommend that you read it carefully. 

If you have any questions regarding the processing of personal data, the contact details of Ecommerce Operations are at the end of this privacy statement. 

Registration
------------

Certain features of our service may require you to register beforehand. You will have to provide some information about yourself and choose a username and password for the account we will set up for you.  

For this purpose, we will gather your name and address details, email address, profile picture, city, country, and language. We need this data to fulfill our obligations under the agreement with you. We store this information for a limited period until you close your account.

We will retain this data so that you do not have to re-enter it every time you use our website or mobile application to contact you in connection with the execution of the agreement, invoicing, and payment (insofar relevant), and to provide an overview of the products and services you have purchased from us.

Contact
-------

You may contact us via [email](mailto:report@scamadviser.com), social media or our [contact form](https://scamadviser.com/contact).  All the personal data which is included in your correspondence with us will be used to provide you with a fitting response or to comply with your request. We store this data for as long as needed for the purposes you have contacted us.

Promotion
---------

We may inform you about new products or services via e-mail or push notifications. You can object at all times against this promotional communication. Every email or push notification contains a cancellation link.

Advertisements
--------------

Our website and mobile application show advertisements. We do not publish these ourselves, but we collaborate with advertising companies. These companies keep track of what you like and use that information to show interesting advertisements or offers in the future. See the section ‘How Advertisers Track ’ for more information.

Phone Number Verification Feature
---------------------------------

Our website and mobile app offers a feature that allows visitors to crosscheck phone numbers against a database of numbers potentially connected to scams. This service is designed to help users identify and avoid fraudulent activities. The database is a combination of various third-party sources, each with their own data categories, as indicated in the phone lookup results.

When you use this feature, we collect the phone number you input for the sole purpose of performing the crosscheck. We do not store this phone number after the check is complete. We also do not use the provided phone numbers for any other purpose, nor do we share them with third-parties.

If you believe that a phone number has been unjustly included in the database, you may submit a removal request. To do so, please follow our notice and takedown procedure as described [here.](https://www.scamadviser.com/notice-and-take-down-procedure) In case the phone number qualifies as your personal data, you may invoke your Right of Rectification as described below under the section “**Your Rights**”.

Providing Data to Third-Parties
-------------------------------

Except for the parties necessary to deliver the above-mentioned services, we do not, under any circumstance, provide your personal data to other companies or organisations unless we are required to do so by law (for example, when the police demand access to personal data in case of a suspected crime).

Our website and mobile application may potentially have social media buttons. These buttons are used by the providers of these services to collect your personal data. For the privacy policies of these providers, see the table under ‘How Advertisers Track’.

How Advertisers Track
---------------------

### ScamAdviser Website

Our website makes use of cookies. Cookies are small files in which we can store information so that you do not have to fill in that information again. We can also use them to see whether you are visiting us again. The first time you visit our website, we will show you a notification explaining our cookies and ask for your permission to use these cookies. You can disable cookies through your browser settings, but some parts of our website may not work correctly as a result. We made arrangements with other parties who place cookies through our website. Insofar as these parties are located outside the EEA, we have taken appropriate measures to ensure that they comply with the GDPR. Nevertheless, we cannot fully control what they do with their cookies, so please read their privacy statements as well. See the list below.

* Google: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads)  
* Ezoic: [https://www.ezoic.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.ezoic.com/privacy-policy/)  
* Twitter: [https://twitter.com/privacy](https://twitter.com/privacy) 
* YouTube: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) 
* Facebook: [https://www.facebook.com/policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy) 
* Next Millenium: [https://nextmillennium.io/next-millennium-media-inc-privacy-policy/](https://nextmillennium.io/next-millennium-media-inc-privacy-policy/) 

In addition, ScamAdviser's website is affiliated with Freestar for the purpose of placing advertising on the website, and Freestar will collect and use specific data for advertising purposes. To learn more about Freestar’s data usage, [click here](https://freestar.com/privacy-policy/).

### ScamAdviser Mobile Applications

In mobile applications (or mobile apps), traditional web cookies, as commonly used on desktop browsers, aren't applicable in the same way. Still, similar mechanisms are used for tracking and data storage purposes. Here are some common methods used in mobile environments: 

* Local Storage: Mobile apps often use built-in data storage options provided by the mobile operating system, such as User Defaults on iOS and Shared Preferences on Android. These mechanisms can store small data, similar to cookies, that persist across user sessions and can be used to save user preferences, login sessions, and other data. 
* SDKs and APIs: Many mobile apps integrate third-party Software Development Kits (SDKs) that facilitate various functionalities, including advertising, analytics, and more. These SDKs can handle data tracking and management, allowing apps to collect, store, and utilise user data for targeted advertising and personalisation. 
* Device IDs: Instead of cookies, mobile apps can track users using unique device identifiers, such as the Google Advertising ID (GAID) for Android devices and the Identifier for Advertisers (IDFA) for iOS devices. Users can reset these IDs, providing them with a degree of control, like clearing cookies. 
* Token-based Authentication: Mobile apps often use tokens to maintain user sessions. Tokens are generated upon successful authentication and sent with subsequent requests to the server. This method is more secure and suited to the stateless nature of mobile interactions compared to traditional cookies. 
* Third-party Tracking Services: Apps may also employ third-party services that utilize their own methods of user tracking and data collection. These might include embedded pixels, SDKs for analytics, or cloud-based user profile storages that aggregate data from multiple sources, including the app itself and other linked services. 

Although mobile apps don't use "cookies" in the traditional sense seen in web browsers, they have developed these alternative methods to achieve similar functionality for user identification, data storage, and personalised advertising. These mechanisms help advertisers deliver targeted content effectively within mobile app ecosystems. 

By installing the ScamAdviser mobile app, you also agree to allow us to enable the methods mentioned above so that advertisers may provide you with targeted advertisements. Where we are legally obliged to obtain your consent before doing so, we will ensure that we obtain such consent. We do not aggregate user behavioural data captured through the above methods to be sold as audience data for retargeting. 

Nevertheless, we cannot fully control what they do with the data they collect, so please read their privacy statements as well. See the list below. 

* Admob: [https://support.google.com/admob/answer/10502938?sjid=4774341004682607568-NC#](https://support.google.com/admob/answer/10502938?sjid=4774341004682607568-NC)  

Google Analytics 
-----------------

We may use Google Analytics to track visitors on our website and mobile application and to get reports about how visitors use them. If we use Google Analytics, we will accept the data processing agreement from Google; however, we won't allow Google to use information obtained by Analytics for other Google services, and we will anonymise the IP addresses. 

Security 
---------

We take security measures to reduce misuse and unauthorised access to personal data. We are responsible for the security of your personal data. We renew our security measures to ensure the safe storage of personal data and keep track of what might go wrong. 

Your Rights 
------------

You can always contact us if you have any questions regarding our privacy policy or wish to review, modify or delete your personal data. 

You have the following rights: 

* Right of Access: you have the right to see what kind of personal data we processed about you; 
* Right of Rectification: you have the right to rectify any personal data we have processed about you if this information is (partially) wrong; 
* Right to Complain: you have the right to file a complaint against the processing of your personal data by us or against direct marketing; 
* Right to be Forgotten: you can file a request with us to remove any personal data we have processed of you; 
* Right to Data Portability: if technically possible, you have the right to ask us to transfer your processed personal data to a third party; 
* Right to Restriction of Processing: You can request that we restrict (temporarily) the processing of your personal data. 

If you exercise any of the abovementioned rights, we might request you identify yourself. 

We will usually respond to your request within 30 days. This term can be extended if the request is proven to be complex or tied to a specific right. You will be notified about a possible extension of this term. 

Changes to this Privacy Statement 
----------------------------------

We reserve the right to modify this statement. We recommend that you consult this statement on a regular basis so that you remain informed of any changes. 

Complaints 
-----------

If you want to file a complaint about our use of personal data, please email [report@scamadviser.com](mailto:report@scamadviser.com) or use our [contact form](https://scamadviser.com/contact). We will investigate and respond to any complaint we receive. 

If you think that we are not helping you in the right way, you have the right to file a complaint with the authority. For The Netherlands, this is the [Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/en). 

Contact Details 
----------------

**Ecommerce Operations B.V.**   
Trading name: ScamAdviser.com   
Keurenplein 41   
UNIT A6311   
1069CD Amsterdam   
The Netherlands 

E: report (at) scamadviser (dot) com

#### Subscribe to our weekly newsletter

SubscribeGO

Thank you!

**For Consumers**

**For Businesses**

**About Scamadviser**

* © 2024 Scamadviser

ScamAdviser is a member of
